翻译: justseven
校订:
原创翻译，望大家多多支持
交流邮箱: jmtrans94@tom.com
双语制作：Dahongying
这是我尚未结束的一天
Here's my day so far:
进了监狱 丢了梦中情人
went to jail, lost the girl of my dreams,
彻彻底底被打败了
and got my butt kicked pretty good.
不过呢 这还不是最惨的
Still, things could be a lot worse.
哦 没错
Oh, that's right.
我要坠入地狱里了
I'm falling to my death.
不会这么快就结局了吧
Guess they can't.
你肯定会问 这么会这样
How'd it all come to this, you ask?
我打一开始就注定会有这结局
My end starts at the beginning.
最开始的时候
The very beginning.
没错 这是我
Yes, that's me.
有一个非常“标准”的童年
I had a fairly standard childhood.
我的家庭可以说是破碎的
I came from, what you might call, a broken home.
真的“破碎”
Literally broken.
(大恐慌) 那时我刚出生八天 还在父母的身边
I was eight days old and still living with my parents.
这么会这么悲哀
How sad is that?
可是那时我只能逃命
Clearly it was time to move on.
这是你的宠物 他会照顾你的
Here is your minion. He will take care of you.
这是你的奶嘴
And here is your binky.
你注定要…
You are destined for...
最后那句我没听见 可是感觉很重要
I didn't quite hear that last part, but it sounded important.
- 二 一 - 注定要干吗
- ...two, one. - Destined for what?
于是我出发寻求我的天命
I set out to find my destiny.
最后发现 从格劳庞克特的孩子 想法都一样的
Turns out a kid from the Glaupunkt quadrant had the exact same idea.
那一天我遇见了那个“伪好男”
That was the day I met Mr. Goody Two-Shoes...
我们辉煌的敌对战就此开始
...and our glorious rivalry was born.
难道这就是我的天命:
Could this be what I was destined for?
一个奢华的梦想生活
A dream life filled with luxury.
显然不是
Apparently not.
即使命运也挑讨人喜欢的
Even fate picks its favorites.
没关系
No big deal.
全然不同的命运等待着我
A much different fate awaited me.
(欢迎来到大都市监狱)
一个婴孩儿 老天有眼
A baby! How thoughtful.
是啊是啊 看到他就能想起你
Oh, yes. Yes, I saw it and thought of you.
幸好我找到了一个可爱的家
Luckily I found a lovely little place to call home.
我们能养他么
Can we keep it?
这个地方教会了我 什么是正确的…
A place that taught me the differences between right...
什么是错误的
...and wrong.
而那位伪好男…
Mr. Goody Two-Shoes, on the other hand,
过着丰衣足食的生活
had life handed to him on a silver platter.
我们的宝宝会飞耶
Our baby can fly.
是啊是啊 只能给你最好的嘛
Yes, yes, nothing but the best for you, darling.
有飞行的超能力 刀枪不入 还有一个好发型
The power of flight, invulnerability, and great hair.
然而我的能力比他更牛
But I had something far, far greater.
我高人一等的智慧…
My amazing intellect...
还有制造大混乱的天赋
...and knack for building objects of mayhem.
几年后 因为表现一直很“良好”…
After a few years, and with some time off for good behavior,
我有机会通过学习充实自己
I was given an opportunity to better myself through learning...
我被送到一个叫“学交”的地方
...at a strange place called shool.
(小天才学校) 在那里 我再一次遇到那个伪好男
It was there that I once again ran into Mr. Goody Two-Shoes.
他已经聚集了一大群没脑子家伙的拥戴
He had already amassed a gigantic army of soft-headed groupies.
他靠表演超能力…
He bought their affections with showmanship
和奢侈的甜品收买人心
and extravagant gifts of deliciousness.
看来我也应该靠“爆掉的米花”来挣回人气
So I, too, will make this popp-ed corn and win over those mindless drones.
熄灯
Lights out.
就在那时 我学到了教训…
That's when I learned a very hard lesson:
正义才能获得赞许与谄媚
Good receives all the praise and adulation,
而邪恶只能 哪儿凉快哪儿呆着去
while evil is sent to quiet-time in the corner.
看来融入群体不是我的选择
So fitting in wasn't really an option.
当他们在学唱儿歌的时候…
While they were learning the Itsy Bitsy Spider...
我学习如何随意将生物 脱水再水合
...I learned how to dehydrate animate objects and rehydrate them at will.
有时候 我感觉这世界只有 宠物是和我站同一阵线的
Some days, it felt like it was just me and Minion against the world.
不管多么努力…
No matter how hard I tried,
我永远都是被排挤的怪人
I was always the odd man out,
最不被接受的一个人…
the last one picked,
受人欺负 成害群之马
the screw-up, the black sheep...
打他
Get him!
- …成一个坏小孩 - 怪胎
- ...the bad boy. - Freak!
怪胎一个
Weirdo!
这就是我的天命么
Was this my destiny?
等一会儿 也许真的是耶
Wait, maybe it was.
我唯一擅长的就是做坏蛋
Being bad is the one thing I'm good at.
我突然想通了 如果我是坏小孩
Then it hit me: If I was the bad boy,
那我就要是全世界最坏的小孩
then I was going to be the baddest boy of them all.
我注定要成为超级大坏蛋
I was destined to be a super-villain,
我们注定要成为敌人
and we were destined to be rivals.
不是他死 就是我亡
The die had been cast,
于是一个毕生永恒的宏大事业 就此展开
and so began an enduring, epic, lifelong career.
我非常敬业的
And I loved it.
(乡村小男孩变坏蛋 世纪之战)
我们的战斗愈变愈烈
Our battles quickly got more elaborate.
(正能胜邪) 有时他赢
He would win some.
(失败者) 其它时候基本我赢
I would almost win others.
人们称它是“城市超人” 大都市的防御者
He took the name Metro Man, defender of Metrocity.
我决定挑一个比较低调的名字 “超级坏蛋麦克迈”
I decided to pick something a little more humble: Megamind...
超英俊的犯罪天才兼罪恶大师
...incredibly handsome criminal genius and master of all villainy.
片名: 超级大坏蛋
(城市超人博物馆开业礼) 拜托你下班再读 开窗
Read on your own time. Open up.
- 嘿 - 磅
- Hey! - Boo!
早上好啊 沃登
Oh, good morning, Warden.
好消息啊 我已经变了
Great news: I'm a changed man, and...
我已经准备好重返社会 做一个好市民
...and I'm ready to re-enter society as a solid citizen.
你是个罪犯 你永远都只能是罪犯
You're a villain, and you'll always be a villain.
你绝不会变的 我也绝不会让你出去
You'll never change, and you'll never Ieave.
你说笑吧
You're fun.
有人送你礼物啊
You got a present in the mail.
是只小狗么
Is it a puppy?
是城市超人送你的 “以计下您第85次终身监禁的每一秒”
From Metro Man. "To count every second of your 85 Iife sentences."
真好笑 没想到他也是个 会幸灾乐祸的人
That's funny. Never thought Metro Man was the gloating type.
哦 他的品味还真不错 我决定留下
Oh, but he does have nice taste. I think I'll keep it.
能不能说下时间
Any chance you could give me the time?
城市超人博物馆的开典礼 我可不想迟到
I don't want to be Iate for the opening of the Metro Man Museum.
哦 不 估计你是要错过了
Oh no. Looks Iike you're gonna miss it,
迟到上千年
by several thousand years.
会吗
Oh, am I?
(隐藏发电机启动) “城市超人日”快乐
Happy Metro Man Day, Metro City.
这是美丽市区 美丽的一天
It's a beautiful day in beautiful downtown,
在这里 我们将迎来敬爱而美丽的人: 城市超人
where we're here to honor a beautiful man, Metro Man.
他的心是无垠海洋 而他心中则是更无垠的海洋
His heart is an ocean that's inside a bigger ocean.
这么多年来 他用自己的超视力 守护着我们
For years he's been watching us with his super-vision,
用他的超能力拯救我们 并用他超凡的心守护我们
saving us with his super-strength and caring for us with his super-heart.
现在该轮到我们报答他了
Now it's our turn to give something back.
我是罗珊.里奇…
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting Iive
从城市超人博物馆现场 为您报道
from the dedication of the Metro Man Museum.
喔 好吧 他们让你念的那段话…
Wow. OK, the stuff they make you read on-air,
真是太可怕了 真夸张
that's un-freaking-believable. It's crazy.
拜托是我自己写的
I wrote that piece myself, Hal.
我想说的是呢…
What I was trying to say was,
不敢相信 在这么个现实社会…
I can't believe that in our modern society,
他们会让你这样的真实艺术 报道新闻
they Iet, Iike, actual art get onto the news.
- 算你会说 哈尔 - 我看我们…
- Nice save, Hal. - What are we...
现在还是去喝杯咖啡休息一下吧
Like, Iet's just get a coffee or something.
拜托 有点“城市超人日”的精神好不好
Come on, it's time to get in the Metro Man Day spirit.
如果我是城市超人
Well, if I were Metro Man,
我绝不会让麦克迈天天绑架你
Megamind wouldn't be kidnapping you all the time.
- 这是我的首要职责 - 你的嘴真甜
- That's the first thing. - That's sweet, Hal.
我会一直守护你 就像狗狗守护着婴孩儿一样
And I'd be watching you, Iike a dingo watches a human baby.
好吧 这么说有点…
OK, that sounded...
- 听起来是有点奇怪 - 却是有点
- OK, that sounded a Iittle weird. - A Iittle bit. Yeah.
你的表情让我更觉得奇怪了
And you're making a weird face, and that's making me feel weird.
反正我是想说 我会一直守护你…
The point is, I would watch you Iike someone...
不是爱 我们没恋爱 我不是说我爱你
Not Iove. We're not in Iove. I'm not saying I Iove you.
我是说 我还是爱你的
Hey, I Iove you. Whatever.
不过我的意思不是恋爱 而是…
But I'm not saying Iike I'm in Iove with you. I'm saying...
罗珊 珊狗狗
Roxanne? Roxaroo?
- 搞什么 - 嘿…
- Whoa... What? - Hey...
回去工作 政府不是雇你们打牌的
Get back to work. The city doesn't pay you to Ioaf.
- 站住 - 喂 你们搞什么
- Freeze! - Whoa. What are you doing, guys?
是我 我是沃登
It's me! It's the warden.
嘿 开门
Hey! Open up!
不 你们这群白痴 他耍了我们
No, you fools. He's tricked us.
你说的对
You were right.
我永远都是罪犯
I'll always be a villain.
你好帅哥 要搭顺风车吗
Well, hello good-Iooking. Need a Iift?
当然要咯 你个帅气的鱼
Certainly do, you fantastic fish, you.
- 上车吧你 - 我自由啦
- Get in the car, you. - I'm free!
哈哈 对吧
Right?
送我表这招不错啊 宠物
Nice work sending me the watch, Minion.
- 你懂的 老大 - 出招吧
- You got it, boss. - Punch it!
好了 把手举高
AII right, put your hands in the air.
女士们 先生们 欢迎你们的城市超人
Ladies and gentlemen, your Metro Man!
- 谁是你们的超人 - 城市超人
- Who's your man? - Metro Man!
好啊 大都市
Yeah, Metro City!
来拍手 快 把手给我
Gimme some. Come on. Give it now.
把手给我 快来 没错
Give it to me. Right on. Gimme the good stuff. AII right.
嘿 大都市
Hey, Metro City.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
来来 我们小声一点
You know, you know, I just want to bring it down a bit.
再小声一点 谢谢 朋友们
Boys, a Iittle Iower. Thank you, fellas.
现在我们言归正传
Let's get real for a moment.
没错 没错 没错
That's right. That's right. That's right.
虽说给我造博物馆 真是太酷太酷了
Although getting a whole museum is super-cool, is super-cool,
可是你们知道你们 赐予我的最高荣耀是什么吗
you want to know what the greatest honor you've given me is?
你们真想知道吗 真的吗
Do you really want to know? Really?
我来告诉你们
I'll tell you.
你们赐予我的最高荣耀 就是让我为你们服务
The greatest honor you've given me is Ietting me serve you,
为大都市无助的人民服务
the helpless people of Metro City.
每天太阳落山之时…
And at the end of every day,
我总是会问自己…
well, I often ask myself...
如果没有你们 我还是什么
...who would I be without you?
- 我爱你 城市超人 - 我也爱你 某某市民
- I Iove you, Metro Man! - And I Iove you, random citizen.
告诉你 宠物 没有地方 比这更像邪恶巢穴了
I tell you, Minion. There's no place Iike evil Iair.
我一直为你让它保持 冰冷潮湿 少爷
I've kept it cold and damp just for you, sir.
我看起来怎么样 宠物 很丑吗
How do I Iook, Minion? Do I Iook bad?
非常恐怖 少爷
Disgustingly horrifying, sir.
你总是那么会说话
You always know what to say.
机器脑可想你了 少爷
Oh, the brain-bots certainly missed you, sir.
你们想爸爸吗 谁是邪恶的机器人
Did you miss your daddy? Who's a menacing Iittle cyborg?
没错 就是你 别咬我
You are. Yes, you are. No biting.
不行 不行 不行
No, no, no, no, no, no.
谁要扳手 去抓扳手
You want the wrench? Go get the wrench.
- 哦 看啊 - 现在可以笑了
- Oh, Iook at that. - Now, back to Iaughing.
她醒了 快去工作
She's awake. Quick, to work.
里奇小姐 我们又见面了
Miss Ritchi, we meet again.
你把袋子洗洗是会死吗
Would it kill you to wash the bag?
你想叫就叫吧 里奇小姐
You can scream all you wish, Miss Ritchi.
可惜没人听得见
I'm afraid no one can hear you.
她…她干吗不叫
Wh... Why isn't she screaming?
里奇小姐 你不介意叫一声吧
Miss Ritchi, if you don't mind?
比如这样
Like this...
那是可怜少妇的尖叫声
But that's, that's a poor Iady scream.
比刚才好多了
He's a Iittle better.
你们是不是上什么 很宅的“超级坏人”网站
Is there some kind of nerdy super-villain Web site
买这些泰斯拉线圈(会产生超高电压的线圈) 和发亮表盘的
where you get Tesla coils and blinky dials?
其实 这些东西大多 是经销店提供的 它在…
Actually, most of it comes from an outlet store in...
别回答
Don't answer that.
- …罗马尼亚 - 别说 住嘴
- Romania. - Don't! Stop!
她会充分利用她 好打听的职业技能…
She's using her nosy reporter skills
打开你薄弱的意志 发现我们所有的秘密
on your weak-willed mind to find out all our secrets.
这种伎俩对我没用的
Such tricks won't work on me...
- 再说慢点 - 小骚货
- Please talk slower. - ...temptress.
什么…秘密… 你的招数那么好猜
What secrets? You're so predictable.
好猜 好猜
Predictable? Predictable?
哦 你说这好猜
Oh, you call this predictable?
你的鳄鱼 是啊
Your alligators. Yes.
我刚刚就猜到了
Yeah, I was thinking about it on the way over.
那这个怎么样 对着你的脸
What's this? Boom! In your face.
- 老套 - 不 你看这个
- Cliche. - No! Look, watch.
- 幼稚 - 吓她一下
- Juvenile. - Shock and awe.
- 俗气 - 哦 这好可怕啊
- Tacky. - Oh, it's so scary!
- 见过了 - 这个怎么样
- Seen it. - What's this one do?
俗不可耐
Garish.
- 好了 蜘蛛倒是蛮新的 - 蜘蛛
- OK, the spider's new. - Spider?
没错 那个… 蜘蛛
Yes. The... The spee-ider.
即使是被这只 “死神蜘蛛”咬一小口
Even the smallest bite from Arachnis deathicus
都会马上麻痹…
will instantly paralyze...
把它弄下 它咬我
Get it off! It bit me!
算了吧 麦克迈 你的计划永远成不了
Give it up, Megamind. Your plans never work.
我们别浪费时间了 你赶紧打电话给你男友 好不
Let's stop wasting time and call your boyfriend in tights, shall we?
我很荣幸为城市超人 展示他的博物馆
It is with great pleasure that I present to Metro Man his new museum.
请剪彩吧
If you please.
- 城市超人 - 嘿 我的孩子看不见了
- Metro Man! - Hey! My kid can't see.
- 麦克迈 - 哦 好呀 城市超人
- Megamind! - Oh, bravo, Metro Man.
嘘
Boo!
我也会玩 嘘
Yes, I can play along too. Boo!
就该意识到你会来派对捣乱
Should've known you'd try to crash the party.
哦 我想的可不只是捣乱
Oh, I intend to do more than crash it.
这一天你和“大兜市”都将难以忘却
This is a day you and Metrocity shall not soon forget.
它念做“大都市”
It's pronounced Metro City!
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮
Potato-tomato, potato-tomato.
我们都已经知道大结局了: 你会被关进监狱里
We all know how this ends: with you behind bars.
我穿着我的“婴儿保护版皮靴”发抖哩
I'm shaking in my custom baby seal leather boots.
要么你离开大兜市 否则这将是你最后一次…
You will leave Metrocity, or this will be the last
听到罗珊.里奇的声音
you ever hear of Roxanne Ritchi.
罗珊 别慌张 珊珊
Roxanne! Don't panic, Roxie.
- 我这就过去 - 我没慌张哦
- I'm on my way. - Yeah, I'm not panicking.
要阻止我 你得先找到我 城市超人
In order to stop me, you need to find me first, Metro Man.
我们在废弃的天文台
We're at the abandoned observatory.
不 才没有呢
No, we're not!
别听她的 她疯了
Don't listen to her. She's crazy.
城市超人正在靠近 少爷
Metro Man approaching, sir.
等会儿
Hold on a second.
哦 老天哪
Oh, good heavens!
你不会真以为自己在 公家的天文台吧
You didn't think you were in the real observatory, did you?
把死亡光波准备好 宠物
Ready the death ray, Minion.
死亡光波 准备
Death ray, readying.
过来 老朋友
Over here, old friend.
我担心你还没发现就告诉你 你已经落入我的圈套里了
In case you haven't noticed, you've fallen right into my trap.
可你无法诱骗正义 因为它是一种思想 一种信念
You can't trap justice. It's an idea, a belief.
即使是最真挚的信仰 随着时间的推移 都会被腐化
Even the most heartfelt belief can be corroded over time.
争议是快防腐的金属
Justice is a non-corrosive metal.
然而金属会被“腐仇之火”熔化
But metals can be melted by the heat of revange.
是叫“复仇” 而且将它冷藏就好
It's "revenge," and it's best served cold.
可是把它放在“邪恶微波炉”里 它还是会被重新熔化
But it can be easily reheated in the microwave of evil.
看来它的保修期就要到了
Well, I think your warranty is about to expire.
我还有一张延时保修单
Maybe I got an extended warranty.
如果产品并非用于正当用途 所有保修单都将无效
Warranties are invalid if you don't use the product for its intended purpose.
哦 姑娘们 姑娘们 你们都很漂亮 我现在能回家了吗
Oh, girls, girls, you're both pretty. Can I go home now?
当然 前提是城市超人 能否承受饱和…
Of course. That is, if Metro Man can withstand the full,
聚合的太阳能
concentrated power of the sun!
发射
Fire!
宠物 发射
Minion. Fire?
- 还在加热 少爷 - 你再说一次
- It's still warming up, sir. - Come again?
- 在加热 少爷 - 加热 太阳是靠加热的吗
- Warming up, sir. - Warming up? The sun is warming up?
还剩一秒就…
One second more and...
再等一丁丁丁…点
...just tippy-tappy tippy-tap-tap, tip-top more,
- 我们就准备好要… - 实在是…
- and we are ready in just... - Honestly!
我就过去 珊珊
On my way, Roxie.
我说过要准备好 我说过无数遍了
I told you to have things ready. I told you countless times.
你干吗老是怪我
Why do you always blame me?
是蜘蛛咬伤在捣乱
My spider bite is acting up.
你的计划失败了 承认了吧
Your plan is failing. Just admit it.
是啊 最好他是会承认
Yeah, good Iuck with that one.
你到底站哪一边的
Whose side are you on?
- 失败的一边 - 谢谢
- The Iosing side. - Thank you.
谁在我的“频繁绑架卡”上盖个章
Could someone stamp my Frequent Kidnapping Card?
你比谁都清楚 我们早就不做那个促销了
You of all people know we discontinued that promotion.
- 拜拜咯 - 下周老时间么
- Ciao-ciao, all! - Same time next week?
啊 蟹肉块
Dag! Crab nuggets!
- 他刚刚说什么 - “蟹肉块”？
- What did he just say? - "Crab nuggets"?
该死的小鱼饼干
Fackled fish cracker!
10秒后能量准备完毕
Ten seconds to full power.
- 老天啊 我被困住了 - 十…
- Good Iord, I'm trapped. - Ten...
- 这又是哪一出戏 - 九…
- What kind of trickery is this? - ...nine...
- 你个可怕的天才 - 八…
- You mad genius. - ...eight...
- 你黑暗的计划终于得逞了 - 七…
- Your dark gift has finally paid off. - ...seven...
- 真…真的吗 - 六…
- It... It has? - ...six...
显然这个圆顶上接有铜线
This dome is obviously Iined with copper.
- 是吗 所以呢 - 少爷…
- Yeah? So? - Sir...
- 铜会吸收我的能量 - 二…
- Copper drains my powers. - ...two...
- 你的弱点就是铜？ - 一
- Your weakness is copper? - ...one.
- 你开玩笑 对吧 - 能量满格
- You're kidding, right? - Full power.
我估计就算他也活不了
I don't think even he could survive that.
我们还是别想得太天真
Well, Iet's not get our hopes up just yet.
- 看 - 城市超人
- Look! - Metro Man!
城市超人耶
Metro Man.
是城市超人啊
Metro Man!
- 你… 你成功了 少爷 - 我成功啦？
- You... You did it, sir. - I did it?
他得逞了
He did it.
- 我成功啦 - 他得逞了
- I did it? - He did it.
- 你成功了 少爷 - 我成功了
- You did it, sir. - I did it!
- 你成功了 - 我成功了 大兜市是我的了
- You did it! - I did it! Metrocity is mine!
- 你成功了 少爷 - 我成功了 对 就是我
- You did it, sir! - I did it! Yeah, me, me!
- 对 我成功了 - 是我们 我们都成功了
- Yes, I did it! - Us! We both did it!
- 不是我们 是我 - 你是比我…
- Not us! I! - You, a Iittle more
- 多一点啦 可还是“我们” - 我比你多很多
- than me but still, come on! - A Iot more than you.
他们给你颁奖的时候
When they're giving out the awards,
- 我要站在你旁边 - 什么奖励 什么奖励 给谁
- I'm gonna be right there next to you. - What awards? What awards, for what?
音乐
Hit it!
放下武器
Drop 'em!
首先呢 风水轮流转啊
First off, what a turnout.
太夸张啦
How wild is this?
我只是把宇宙最强悍的人消灭掉了
AII I did was eliminate the most powerful man in the universe.
有什么问题吗 问吧 请说 你的后面
Are there any questions? Go on. Yes! You in the back.
我们都想知道你想对我们 对这个城市做什么
I'm sure we'd all Iike to know what you plan to do with us and this city.
很好 你问这问题我很开心
Good, I'm glad you asked that.
想一个你能想到的 最恐怖…
Imagine the most horrible, terrifying,
吓人 邪恶的事情
evil thing you can possibly think of,
我给你们的 就是它的六倍
and multiply it... by six!
同时呢…
In the meantime,
我要你们继续你们 无趣普通的事情…
I want you to carry on with the dreary, normal things
你们这些普通人
you normal people do.
你们先High起来庆祝吧 快点
Let's just have fun with this. Come on.
我等会儿就回来
And I will get back to you.
现在重重地甩门
Now slam the door really hard.
他们… 他们还是能看到你
They... They can still see you.
- 现在呢 - 你的胳膊还是看得到
- Now? - Your elbow's still in.
很好
Good.
邪恶霸主先生到来
There he is, Mr. Evil Overlord
哦 宠物 你能想到 这一天会到来吗
Oh, Minion, did you think this day would ever come?
不可能 根本想不到 少爷
No way. Not at all, sir.
绝不 丝毫也不… 我是说…
Never. Never in a million... I mean...
- 没错 我想过 - 看这些交错的线条
- Yes, I did. - Look at the intricate mouldings.
我在看啦 我在看
I'm Iooking. I'm Iooking.
看这是什么
And what's this?
像是巢穴里的巨大监视器
It's Iike one of the giant monitors in the Iair.
可它好像只能监视一个点
But it seems to only carry one station.
哦 那个啊 少爷 它叫窗户
Oh, that, sir, is called a window.
- 窗户啊 - 小孩都喜欢朝窗户望的
- Window? - AII the kids are Iooking through them.
我以前都没从窗户望出过咧
I've never had a view before.
大兜市啊 我的宠物 它都是我的
Metrocity, Minion, it's all mine.
真希望我父母现在能看见我
If my parents could see me now.
少爷 我肯定他们在邪恶的天堂上 往下对你微笑呢
Sir, I'm sure they're smiling down from evil heaven.
既然现在伪好男先生已经滚蛋了
And now that Mr. Goody Two-Shoes is out of the way,
(麦克迈 邪恶霸主) 现在我想要什么就有什么
I can have everything I want,
谁也阻止不了我了
and there's no one to stop me!
(不 你们不能) (奥巴马的口号是“是的 我们能”)
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
永远饥渴 从不满足
Always thirsty, never satisfied.
我理解你 衣着入时的小鸟
I understand you, Iittle well-dressed bird.
无目的的 空虚的 就像真空一样
Purposeless, emptiness. It's a vacuum, isn't it?
就像… 你的真空什么样
It's... What's your vacuum Iike?
嘿 嘿… 想在不行 宠物
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Not now, Minion.
我正在进行激烈的存在主义讨论
I'm in a heated, existential discussion
和这个死眼的台桌塑料玩具
with this dead-eyed, plastic desk toy.
是…是出什么事了吗 少爷
Is... Is something wrong, sir?
你想一想
Just think about it.
我们什么都有了
We have it all.
可我们还是一无所有
Yet, we have nothing.
感觉什么都太轻松了
It's just too easy now.
对不起 我没听懂 少爷
I'm sorry, you've Iost me, sir.
我是说 我们成功了 对吧
I mean, we did it, right?
呃 是你成功了 少爷
Well, you did it, sir.
是的 你已经说得很清楚了
Yes, you've made that perfectly clear.
那为什么我还觉得 那么…“愚闷”
Then why do I feel so... mel-on-choly.
“愚闷”？
"Mel-on-choly"?
- 不开心 - 呃…
- Unhappy. - Well...
如果明天…
What if tomorrow,
我们去绑架罗珊.里奇
we could go kidnap Roxanne Ritchi.
这总该能让你振奋了吧
That always seems to Iift your spirits.
好主意 宠物 可没有了他 还有什么意义
Good idea, Minion. But without him, what's the point?
- 他是谁 - 谁也不是
- "Him," sir? - Nothing.
好吧 这样 我们可以… 还是有事情可以考虑的…
OK, all right. We'll just... that's something to consider...
我看我先关机断电一会儿了
...and... Well, I think I'll just power down for a while then.
他总是为了我们 他可靠
He was always there for us. Dependable.
也许我们太把他当做理所当然了
Perhaps we took him for granted. You know, maybe,
也许在他走之前 我们都还 不清楚拥有他的好处
we never really know how good we have it until it's gone.
我们想念你 城市超人 我想你
We miss you, Metro Man. I miss you.
我只是有个问题想问麦克迈 你现在开心了吧
And I have just one question for Megamind: Are you happy now?
我是罗珊.里奇 从失去英雄的都市发来的报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting from a city without a hero.
接下来 如果你想加入奴役军队 也许你应该了解以下内容
Coming up next, are you ready to be a slave army? What you need to know.
大功告成 当做送小孩的圣诞礼物 (这里wrap up双关: 有结束和包裹礼物的意思)
And... wrap that up and give it to a child on Christmas,
- 我们完工了 - 好吧 明天见 哈尔
- 'cause we're done. - OK. See you tomorrow, Hal.
等会儿 罗罗 我在我家举办派对
Wait. Roxie, I'm having a party at my house.
估计会超棒的
It's gonna be, Iike, off the hook, or whatever.
你应该来玩玩 我有请DJ啊
You should come over. I got a deejay,
租了个弹跳屋(小孩玩的充气小屋) 还做了一加仑的沙司
rented a bouncy house, made a gallon of dip.
肯定很可怕
It's gonna be sick.
哦 我不知道啊 哈尔
Oh. I... I don't know, Hal.
我今天没心情跟一群人High
I don't really feel Iike being around a bunch of people.
不 不 不 最棒的就是 聚会将只有你和我
No, no, no, that's the best part. It'll just be Iike you and me.
喔 真的是 肯定很诱人 可…
Wow. That... that's certainly very tempting, but...
我请了婚礼摄影师 以防我们做什么…
I did hire a wedding photographer. That's just in case we were Iike,
好笑的事情 然后可以让他拍照
something crazy happened and we wanted a picture of it.
可以让他拍张照 好作纪念什么的 对吧
Like, maybe we should have this for, Iike, ever. Like a memory, you know?
我还是算了
I'm gonna pass.
我还有工作要做呢
I have some work here that I need to do, anyway.
好吧 那周四怎样 轻松的星期四
Cool. So Thursday? Soft Thursday?
- 晚安 哈尔 - 就是说周四可以了
- Good night, Hal. - That's a soft yes on Thursday.
我到底搞什么啊 什么租了个弹跳屋
What's wrong with me? Rented a bouncy house?
女人怎么会喜欢弹跳屋啊
Chicks don't Iike bouncy houses.
她们喜欢的是小丑
They Iike clowns.
这辆蠢车 你弄断我指头了
Stupid van! You broke my finger!
我真是太犯蠢了
I've made a horrible mistake.
我不是有意消灭你的
I didn't mean to destroy you.
我是说 我本来是想消灭你
I mean, I meant to destroy you,
可我以为肯定又没成功
but I didn't think it would really work.
我们现在该怎么办
What are we supposed to do?
没了你 恶势力四处猖獗
Without you, evil is running rampant through the streets.
我已经厌倦如恶魔般四处猖獗
I'm so tired of running rampant through the streets.
没有干扰你的过程
What's the point of being bad
我当坏蛋还有什么意义
when there's no good to try and stop you?
必须有人来阻止麦克迈
Someone has to stop Megamind.
- 我们要关门了 - 你吓到我了
- Hey, we're closing soon. - You scared me.
- 你是巴里吧 - 是伯纳德
- Barry, right? - Bernard.
伯纳德 我是在… 我在自言自语
Bernard. I was just... Well, I was talking to myself.
你可能会觉得我有点神经
You probably think I'm a Iittle bit nuts.
我不让直接羞辱客人
I'm not allowed to insult guests directly.
谢谢 只是… 伯纳德 我想再呆一会儿
Thank you. Just... Bernard, I'll just be another minute.
好吧
OK.
谢谢
Thanks.
我本来还有很多的邪恶计划
I had so many evil plans in the works.
比如文盲光束
The illiteracy beam.
台风奶酪
Typhoon cheese.
机器绵羊
Robo-sheep.
可是我们永远都无法开战了
Battles we will now never have.
我都没机会跟你说再见
You know, I never had the chance to say goodbye.
还好现在我们能拥有这一刻
So it's good that we have this time now.
让我在摧毁博物馆前一吐为快
You know, before I destroy the place.
摧毁这里不是针对你 只是它给我带来太多伤心记忆
Nothing personal, it just brings back too many painful memories.
是谁
Hello?
- 谁在那里 - 罗珊
- Hello? - Roxanne.
- 你这戏服太没品味了吧 - 你说戏服
- That's a pretty tasteless costume. - Costume?
麦克迈的脑子也不过如此
Megamind's head is not that grossly exaggerated.
(脱水)
And you even made a cheap replica of his dehydration gun. How...
你居然还仿造他做了支 廉价的脱水枪 无语了…
谁在那里啊
Hello? Is someone there?
喂 那边是谁
Hello? Who's there?
是你啊 伯纳德
It's just you, Bernard.
没错 是我 伯纳德…
Yes. It's just me. Bernard.
谢谢你让我呆那么久
Well, thank you for Ietting me stay.
要是我 我绝不会再在这里停留…
Look, I wouldn't stay here for more than two minutes and 37 seconds
超过2分钟37秒 因为墙和天花板要拆了
if I were you. We're having the walls and ceiling removed.
听起来像是个大翻修
Wow, that sounds Iike quite the renovation.
我看还是跟你搭电梯下去吧
I guess I'll catch a ride down with you then.
我一直以为他会 在最后一分钟成功逃脱
I kept thinking he was gonna do one of his Iast-minute escapes.
是啊 他还是很擅长这样的
Yeah. He was really good at those.
真希望这世界 也能装一个重置开关
Oh, if only the world had a reset button.
我研究过重置开关
I've Iooked into the reset button.
我的科研办不到
The science is impossible.
哦 伯纳德…
Oh, Bernard...
我没想到你也这么…多愁伤感 你还好吗
I didn't know you had... feelings. Are you OK?
城市超人走了 现在没人 能来挑战麦克迈了
Metro Man's gone. And now there's no one Ieft to challenge Megamind.
别这样想 伯纳德
Oh, come on, Bernard.
只要有一丝邪恶尚存 总会有正义出面抵抗的
As Iong as there's evil, good will rise up against it.
哦 我也希望
Oh, I wish.
我相信总有人会站出来 反抗麦克迈的
I believe someone is gonna stand up to Megamind.
- 你真这么想 - 是啊 不是有句俗话么
- You really think so? - Yeah. I mean, it's Iike they say,
“英雄不是天生的 是后天造就的”
"Heroes aren't born, they're made."
英雄可以造就 没错
Heroes can be made. That's it!
你只需要适当的配料
AII you need are the right ingredients.
- 没错 勇气 - 是的
- Yeah. Bravery. - Yes.
- 力量 - 没错
- Strength. - Of course.
- 毅力 - 必须的
- Determination. - Imperative!
还有一小段DNA 哦 有了它 谁都能成为英雄
And a smidgen of DNA. Oh, with that, anyone can be a hero!
是啊
Yeah!
我们该走了
I think we should run!
拜
Bye!
是时候抛弃过去了
Time to put the past behind us.
只要未来…
Only the future...
站太近了 我现在真吓到了
I'm too close! I'm genuinely scared right now.
真希望没人会看到
I hope no one's seeing this!
制造一个英雄 等会儿 什么啊 你干吗要这样
Create a hero? Wait, wait, what? Why would you do that?
好让我有人去对抗啊
So I have someone to fight.
宠物 我是个没有英雄的罪犯
Minion, I'm a villain without a hero.
道教上就是阳的阴
A yin with no yang.
一个没有斗牛的斗牛士
A bullfighter with no bull to fight.
总而言之 我没有生活的目的
In other words, I have no purpose.
现在 快问我要怎么解决 快问啊 快
Now, ask me how I'm going to do it. Go on! Ask!
你打算怎么做
How are you gonna do it?
我打算给某个人―― 虽说还不知道是谁――
I'm going to give someone... I don't know who yet...
城市超人的超能力
Metro Man's powers.
我要训练那个人成为 大兜市的新英雄
I'm going to train that someone to become Metrocity's new hero.
过来 快跟上
Over here! Follow!
最后 我要在史上的正邪之战中…
And then finally, I'm going to fight that hero
与那个英雄对抗
in an epic battle of good and evil.
这样我们就能 让世界恢复原来…
Which will put everything back the way it was...
完美如意的样子
...when the world was perfect and rosy.
看着吧 宠物 这是城市超人的斗篷
Behold, Minion, Metro Man's cape.
靠近点看 告诉我你看到了什么
Look closely. Tell me what you see.
- 头皮屑 - 没错 他的DNA
- Dandruff? - Yes. It's his DNA.
在这里 我们将提取出 城市超人的能力之源
From this, we'll extract the source of Metro Man's awesome power.
少爷 我看这主意不怎样
Sir, I think this is a bad idea.
没错 对于最仁慈的人来说 这主意是不怎么样
Yes! This is a very wickedly bad idea for the greater good of man.
我说的不怎样是说它…
But I'm saying this is a kind of bad that...
好吧 以你的想法上看 这主意是不错
...OK, you might think is good in your bad perception,
可是以好的方面看 这主意就是很糟
but from a good perception it... it's just plain bad.
你不懂 对于坏人 什么是好
Oh, you don't know what's good for bad.
现在 我们只要开一枪
Now, we have just one shot at this.
我们必须找到合适的目标 一个拥有高尚心灵的人
We must find a suitable subject, someone of noble heart and mind.
(注入)
一个将大众利益摆在 个人利益之上的人
Who puts the welfare of others above their own.
那是什么东西
What on Earth is that?
好像是从这里传出的 少爷
It seems to be emanating from there, sir.
(来电)
李好
OIIo.
是“你好”
It's "Hello."
你好 是这样吗
Hello? Like that?
- 伯纳德 我是罗珊 - 是罗珊
- Bernard, it's Roxanne. - It's Roxanne.
我想谢谢你那天激励了我
I just wanted to thank you for inspiring me the other day.
- 哦 你也激励了我 - 真棒
- Oh, you inspired me too. - Great!
是时候站出来告诉麦克迈 我们不是任由他摆布的
It's time we stood up to Megamind and show him he can't push us around.
哦 是吗 她真可爱
Oh, really? She's so cute.
我发现了他的行踪
I'm already hot on his trail.
- 你又是怎么知道的啊 - 少爷
- And what gives you that idea? - Sir?
我找到他的秘密巢穴了
I just found his secret hideout.
她是怎么知道我的巢穴的
How did she find my hideout?!
你怎么知道他的巢穴的
How did you find his hideout?
整个大都市就这里 屋顶上有假天文台啦
This is the only building in Metro City with a fake observatory on the roof.
好吧 反正她也找不到秘密入口
OK. There's no way she'll find the secret entrance.
啊 这里竟然有个地垫 上面写着“秘秘入口”
There's a doormat here that says "Secrit Entrance"!
- 宠物 - 我一直忘记它放哪儿了
- Minion! - I kept forgetting where it was.
她会发现我们所有的秘密的
She'll discover all our secrets!
- 哦 不 - 你个科研蠢货
- Oh, no! - You dim-witted creation of science!
- 什么 - 哦不 不是指你 罗珊
- What? - What? Oh, no, not you, Roxanne.
我是在对我… 妈妈的骨灰盒嚷嚷
No, I was just yelling at my... mother's urn.
什么都别做 我这就过去
Don't do anything. I'll be right there.
罗珊
Roxanne?
哦 不 又来了
Oh no, not again!
罗珊
Roxanne?
真高兴你来了 你怎么来那么快啊
I'm glad you're here. Wait, how did you get here so fast?
这样 你打给我的时候 我刚好在竞走呢
Well, I... I happened to be speed walking nearby when you called.
穿着西服吗
In a suit?
这叫做… 正装竞走 这不是重点啦
It's called... formal speed walking, but that's not important.
我带头比较好 这边走好像很刺激
I better take the Iead. This way Iooks exciting.
不行 上面写着“出口”
No, it says "Exit."
那是“刺激”的缩写对吧 (出口“exit” 刺激“exciting”)
Which is the abbreviation for "exciting," right?
重大发现
This is the mother Iode!
- 喔 瞧这玩意儿 - 喔
- Wow. Just Iook at this thing. - Wow.
我确实需要你帮我破解这些东西
You know, I really could use your help in deciphering all this.
- 是吗 - 你不是…
- Really? - You're an expert
- 麦克迈方面的专家 - 是啊 对
- on all things Megamind, right? - Yes. Right.
我们一起就能找到阻止他 摧毁城市的办法了
Together, we could figure out his plan for the city and stop it.
- 你要加入吗 - 哦 肯定好玩
- Are you in? - Oh, what fun!
我就是要听你这么说
That's what I want to hear.
宠物 暗号: 把机器脑们带过来
Minion, Code: Send In The Brain-bots.
你知道什么叫暗号吧…
You know, the whole point of a code is...
好吧 暗号: 动手吧 宠物
Oh, Code: Just Do It, Minion.
入侵者 入侵者…
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
- 是我啦 白痴 - 伯纳德
- It's me, you fools! - Bernard!
是老爸
It's Daddy!
麦克迈
Megamind.
- 你把伯纳德怎么样了 - 哦 伯纳德啊 对
- What have you done with Bernard? - Oh, Bernard? Oh, yes.
我对那个人做了很可怕的事
I'm doing horrible things to that man.
我不是很想说 不过激光啊 长钉啊
I don't want to get into it, but Iasers, spikes.
不要 拜托不要 不要激光和长钉
No, please! No! Not the Iasers and the spikes!
- 你知道钻头的 - 哦 不 不要钻头
- You know the drill. - Oh, no! Not the drill!
- 放他走 否则… - 否则怎样
- Let him go or... - Or what?
否则我倒要看看 这怪怪的枪干吗用的
Or I'm gonna find out what this weird-Iooking gun does.
不 别开枪 你别开枪
No, don't shoot! Don't shoot that gun!
我直接搞定他吧
I'll just go get him.
- 你手放开 你个恶魔 - 绝不
- Unhand me, you fiend! - Never!
他的力气太大了
His strength's too much!
哦 我有锻炼的
Oh, I work out!
看来是有成效的 你这么壮…
Well, it's really paying off! You're so fit,
有这么有魅力
and strangely charismatic.
你还好吧
Are you OK?
我尽力了 可他太强悍了
I did my best, but he's too fantastic.
来 让我帮你拿着那么沉的枪
Here. Let me carry that heavy gun for you.
我来作掩护
I got us covered.
- 放手 它是我的 - 伯纳德快跑
- Let go. It's mine! - Bernard, run!
罗珊
Roxanne?
- 你要弄坏它了 - 把它给我
- You're going to break it! - Give it to me!
哦 不
Oh, no!
罗珊
Roxanne?!
那是谁啊
Who on Earth is that?
- 救命 - 罗珊
- Help! - Roxanne!
伯纳德 你说得对 那扇门确实很刺激
Bernard! You were right about that door being exciting.
- 入侵者 入侵者 - 这边走
- Intruder! Intruder! - This way.
入侵者 入侵者…
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
你在干吗
What are you doing?
这应该能阻止他们 接着
This'll stop them. Here!
这也太极端了吧
Seems a bit extreme, doesn't it?
- 快扔吧 - 老爸对不起你们
- Just throw it! - Daddy's sorry.
- 喔 真是太刺激了 - 是啊
- Wow. That was really exciting. - Yeah.
- 你在里面真强悍 - 我知道
- You were very strong in there. - I know.
除了城市超人 我还没见过谁 能像你一样与他抗衡
I've never seen anyone but Metro Man stand up to him Iike that.
- 怎么啦 - 哈尔 你怎么了
- What's going on? - Hal, what happened?
感觉是一只蜜蜂飞进我鼻子里了
I think a bee flew up my nose.
我正准备打头炮拯救你呢
I was just about to make my frontal assault to rescue you,
可好像有50个忍者想要攻击我 我必须先把他们撂倒
but Iike 50 ninjas tried to attack me, so I had to beat 'em all up,
我成功了 然后我… 他们就都哭了…
and I did, and I... They were all, Iike, crying and stuff...
- 喔 好勇敢啊 是吧 - 你是谁
- Wow, a brave one, isn't he? - Who are you?
哦 这位是伯纳德 他是我搭档
Oh, thi... this is Bernard. He's my partner.
- 搭档 - 对 对啊 搭档
- Partner? - Yes. Yes. Partner.
听着 这位“搭档” 我才是她的搭档 她不知道她在说什么
Well, Iook, "partner," I'm her partner. She doesn't know what she's saying.
她刚经受了精神的创伤
She's been through a traumatic experience.
我最好先带他回去 再次谢谢你 伯纳德
I'd better take him home. Thanks again, Bernard.
我明天再打给你 搭档
I'll call you tomorrow, partner.
是啊 好啊 我很开心
Yeah, OK. I'd Iike that.
这对谁都太奇怪了
That was weird for everybody,
因为你竟突然拥抱他 而不是我
'cause you accidentally hugged him instead of me.
少爷 少爷
Sir? Sir!
暗号: 你知道那是谁了吗
Code: Did You Find Out Who It Was?
暗号: 把车开来
Code: Get The Car.
暗号: 这就来 少爷
Code: Right Away, Sir.
- 拜拜 - 明天见 哈尔
- Bye-bye! - See you tomorrow, Hal.
我门不会锁 方便你等会儿来看我
I'll Ieave the door unlocked in case you want to check on me Iater.
刚被我们注射 神一般能力的人是谁呢
Who is this man we've infused with godlike power?
少爷 他的名字叫哈尔.斯图尔特 今年28岁
Well, sir, his name's Hal Stewart. He's 28 years old.
没有犯罪记录 什么记录都没有
No criminal record. Actually no records at all.
显然这家伙一无是处
Apparently this man hasn't accomplished anything.
还没到时候 宠物 还没到呢
Not yet, Minion. Not... yet.
这天就不能再有趣点吗
Could this day get anymore fun-tastic?
我还是把它消散好了 显然这一切都只是个错误
So, I will just go ahead and diffuse him since this is clearly a mistake.
不行 宠物 这还是有大用处的
No, Minion! There's something much more powerful at work here.
没有错误 只有命运
This is no mistake. It's destiny.
哈尔.史图尔特 准备迎接你的命运吧
Hal Shtewart! Prepare for your destiny!
哈尔 哈尔.史图尔特
Hal? Hal Shtewart?
- 嘿 在床上呢 - 我有念错吗
- Hey! In the bed! - Am I saying it right?
是“斯图尔特”
"Stewart."
是抢劫吗
Is this a robbery?
因为对面那个妇人 比我富裕多了
'Cause the Iady across the hall has way better stuff than me.
哦 看 是哈尔.斯图尔特 快 快喷
Oh, Iook, it's Hal Stewart. Quick, the spray.
用光了
AII out.
- 那就用“忘我棒” -  哦 对
- Well, use the Forget-Me Stick. - Oh, right.
你看他
Just Iook at him.
他怎么看都不像是个英雄
No, he doesn't Iook quite the hero-type to me.
你真是讨厌啊 宠物
Oh, you're such a pill, Minion.
陶工不会挑黏土的好坏
A potter couldn't ask for finer clay.
我闻到英雄的味道
I smell a hero.
我看好像什么着火了
I smell something burning.
我看是起作用了 让开 让开
I think it's working. Places! Places!
让开 让开 让开
Places! Places! Places.
带上你的扮装了吗
Do you have your disguise?
怎么
What?
哦 你看着很好
Oh, you Iook fantastic.
起来吧 我的荣耀
Rise my glorious creation.
起来吧 来你爸爸身边
Rise, and come to Papa.
- 怎么回事 - 放松 我的孩子
- What's going on? - Easy my child.
- 你是谁 - 我派你来这个星球
- Who are you? - I sent you to this planet
教你何谓正义 荣耀与高尚
to teach you about justice, honor, and nobility.
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
所以你算是我的太空老爸
So you're Iike my space dad?
是啊 我算是你的太空老爸
Yeah, I'm Iike your space dad.
那你是什么
And you are what?
我是你的太空继母
I'm your space stepmom.
我最近做了点美容
I've had some work done recently.
这是什么梦吗
Is this some kind of dream?
是你的梦成真了
This is a dream come true.
你被赐予“高森莫测”的能力了
You've been blessed with unfathomable power.
- 什么能力 - 高森莫测
- What kind of power? - Unfathomable.
就是高森… 就是难以预测
It's unf... without fathom.
是啊 我们是来引导你的
Yeah. We've come to guide you
帮助你成为大兜市的新英雄
on your path to be Metrocity's new hero
并与超级天才麦克迈决斗
and battle the super-genius of Megamind.
我知道这有点难接受
I know this is a Iot to take in.
可能要花好几个月才能让你领会
It may take months for you to come to grips.
不是吧
No freaking way!
我没说完呢
I wasn't finished.
我就是英雄啦
I'm gonna be a hero!
我就要是英雄啦
看哪 宠物 他太完美了
See, Minion, he's perfect!
现在 开始
And... action!
- 救命啊 - 我没问题
- Someone help me! - I'm OK!
你 坏蛋
You... Bad!
死掉 死掉…
Zap! Zap! Zap!
我邪恶的火焰愈发明亮
The flames of my evil burn bright.
现在你回呛我
Now you say something cool back at me.
你看 不会痛耶 一点感觉都没有
Look. It doesn't even hurt. Don't even feel it.
不不不 肚子向下 手向上 像城市超人一样
No, no, no, no, no. Stomach down, hands up. Like Metro Man.
- 喔 等会儿 - 当心
- Whoa! Wait! - Watch out.
他没救了 没救了
He's hopeless. Hopeless!
- 也许我们应该改变战略 - 你真这么想
- Maybe we should change tactics. - You think so?
你也知道男孩子嘛
Oh, you know how boys are.
(来图书馆见我 罗珊) 都喜欢玩游戏机的
They Iove video games.
- 我能随便拼凑几个 - 等不及了
- I could throw a few parts together. - Can't wait.
大笑 笑脸
LOL. Smiley face.
等不及干吗啊 少爷
Can't wait for what, sir?
这故事真是太好笑啦
That was such a funny story.
说得太好了
And brilliantly told, by the way.
现在轮你说了
OK, now you tell one.
伯纳德 我从没发现 你会这么有趣
Bernard, I never knew you were so funny.
我以前也从没听过你笑
And I never heard you Iaugh before.
是啊 很久了 感觉蛮好的
Yeah, it's been a while. Feels pretty good.
(《麦克迈的战争》)
(《揭露麦克迈》)
现在开始
And action.
搞定你
Gotcha!
- 你不怎么经常出来玩吧 - 哦 太好玩了
- You don't get out much, do you? - Oh, what fun!
我还小的时候 经常和妈妈来这里
I used to come here with my mother when I was a kid.
那是我当时最喜欢的事情之一
It was one of my favorite things to do.
现在你看 脏得不行
Now Iook at it. It's a dump.
我们干吗要清理城市呢 少爷
Why are we cleaning up the city, sir?
我们才不愿意战争是在 垃圾场里开打的 对吧
Well, we don't want to battle our new hero in a dump now, do we?
它们都回来了 怎么会 为什么
They're all back. But how? Why?
可能麦克迈也没那么坏
Maybe Megamind isn't so bad after all.
没错
That's it.
自由吧 我美丽的鸽子
Be free, my beautiful dove!
好吧 好吧
OK, OK.
我和城市超人从不是一对
Metro Man and I were never a couple.
- 我以为你们俩是… - 我知道 谁都这么想
- But I thought you two were... - I know. Everybody did.
只是 他从不是我的菜
It's just... Well, he was never really my type.
真的吗
Really?
现在换你说了
OK, now you tell me something.
说你从没告诉别人的事
Something you've never told anyone.
嗯 在学交…校
Well, in sh... school...
没有一个孩子喜欢我
...none of the other kids really Iiked me.
永远都是我挑剩下的
I was always the Iast one picked for everything.
我们竟然没上同一所学校 真可惜
It's too bad that we didn't go to the same school.
哈尔 我想你已经准备好了
Hal, I think you're ready for this.
- 我有儿子啦 - 不是啦
- Do I have a son? - No.
你老是让我想笑
You make me Iaugh.
它能拉伸的 是给你的
It stretches. It's for you.
T代表什么
Hey, what's the T stand for?
泰坦
Titan.
“泰坦” 是什么意思
"Titan"? What's that supposed to mean?
是我唯一能注册的商标
It was the only name I could trademark.
谁是你生命中最特殊的人 哈尔
Do you have someone special in your Iife, Hal?
不 还没有 不过… 倒是有个非常美的姑娘
No, not yet. But... there's this really, really good-Iooking one
我最近一直盯着她
I've got my eye on currently.
这很好啊
That's very good.
- 浪漫总能振奋人心 - 说的不错
- Romance is very inspiring. - That's what I hear.
你要做的就是去拯救她 那她就会是你的了
AII you have to do is save her and she'll be yours.
- 谁要西班牙油条 - 我要
- Who wants churros? - I do!
- 我也要 谢谢 太空后妈 - 永远的西班牙油条
- I do, yeah. Thanks, Space Stepmom. - Churros all the way around.
我数到三 抽出你的油条
On the count of three, unsheathe your churro.
一 二 三
One, two, three!
为泰坦
To Titan!
明天 你将对战麦克迈 这座城市将记住你的名字
Tomorrow, you will fight Megamind, and the city will know your name.
城市公园又恢复它们原有的美丽
...the city's parks restored to their original glory,
街道比以往更安全 银行也都重新开业了
the streets the safest they've been, the banks reopened.
难道麦克迈发生什么事了吗
Has something happened to Megamind?
难道是谁驯服了这只猛兽了吗
Has someone tamed this monster?
我是罗珊.里奇 有些乐观
This is Roxanne Ritchi, cautiously optimistic,
愉悦而困惑
and pleasantly confused.
看来你今晚很开心啊 少爷
Well, you seem in a very good mood tonight, sir.
哦 对啊 这到底要花 多长时间 宠物
Oh, yes. How Iong is this going to take, Minion?
再做一些改变 少爷 然后我就…
Just a few alterations, sir, and I will be done
把你最恐怖的披风搞定了
with your most terrifying cape yet!
我打算叫它…
I'm calling it...
黑色眼镜蛇
...the Black Mamba...
黑色眼镜蛇 很不错
Black Mamba. Perfect.
老天哪 快迟到了 我得走了
Gosh, I am running Iate. I have to go.
什么 你… 你去哪里 少爷
What? Where... Where are you going, sir?
明天早上我们有一场 和泰坦战斗的首演
We have our debut battle with Titan tomorrow morning.
我们都还没测试你的大战服呢
We haven't even tested your big battle suit yet.
你处理细节吧 宠物 我有…有急事要跑腿
You attend to the details, Minion. I have to... run a quick errand.
你从不跑腿的
You don't run errands.
- 到底怎么回事 - 什么
- What's going on here? - What?
哦 等一会儿
Oh, wait a minute.
你是不是喷了高缇耶男士香水
Are you wearing Jean Paul Gaultier's Pour Homme?
那是我真实的体香 现在 我的车钥匙呢
It's just my natural musk. Now, where are the car keys?
这都跟里奇小姐有关 对吧
This is about Ms. Ritchi, isn't it?
你要跟她约会
You're going on a date with her.
才不呢 我的朋友 算了吧
No, my main man. Get out of town.
糟糕了 糟糕了 你爱上她了
Oh, this is bad. This is bad. You've fallen in Iove with her.
别忘了你的地位 宠物 把钥匙还我
You are forgetting your place, Minion. Now give me the keys.
要是罗珊发现你的真实面目怎么办
What happens when Roxanne finds out who you really are?
她绝不会发现的 这才是撒谎的关键
She will never find out. That's the point of Iying.
说真的 要不是早就认识你
Honestly, if I didn't know any better,
我肯定以为你是在第一天使坏
I'd think this was your first day of being evil.
不行
No!
这一切都到此为止
This has gone far enough!
现在倒是长大了嘛
Oh, that was really grown-up!
少爷 少爷 求你了 这也是为你好
Sir, sir, please. It's for your own good.
哦 你怎么知道
Oh, what do you know?
我可能知道的不多 但我清楚一点
I may not know much, but I do know this:
坏蛋永远钓不到女孩
The bad guy doesn't get the girl.
也许我再也不想当坏人了
Maybe I don't want to be the bad guy anymore.
你听到了
You heard me!
你是谁
Who are you?
- 现在把钥匙给我 - 不要
- Now, give me the keys! - No!
我此生唯一的目的就是照顾你
My sole purpose in Iife is to Iook after you.
可我不需要你照顾我
Well, I don't need you to Iook after me.
你说… 你说什么 你不需要我
What are you s... What are you saying? You don't need me?
让我说清楚吧 暗号: 我不需要你
Let me make it clear. Code: I Don't Need You.
你知道吗 你知道吗
You know what? You know what?
暗号: 我还是卷铺盖走人吧
Code: I'll Just Pack My Thing And Go!
- 暗号: 很好 - 暗号: 我也很好
- Code: Fine! - Code: Fine Back!
- 祝你约会好运吧 - 会的
- Well, good Iuck on your date! - I will!
- 根本就没道理嘛 - 我知道
- That doesn't even make any sense! - I know!
就知道我就要找到了 我能感觉得到
I know I am so close. I can feel it.
好吧好吧 让我退一步想想
OK, OK. I just have to take a step back.
等一会儿
Wait a minute.
泰坦
"Titan."
- 泰坦是什么 - 我的超级耳朵在燃烧
- What's a Titan? - My super-ears are burning.
我通常只听到罪犯的声音 你应该还没变调皮吧
I usually just hear criminals. You haven't been naughty, have you?
你肯定搞糊涂了吧 我把你搞糊涂了
I'm totally messing with you. I'm totally messing with you.
- 我叫泰坦 - 泰坦
- The name's Titan. - Titan.
你最富英雄气概的强悍保卫者
Your very own heroic guardian of pure awesome.
你叫什么 开玩笑啦 你的事我都知道
What's your name? Just kidding. I know everything about you.
我还带了些花
And I... And I brought some flowers.
不知道你喜欢什么 所以我把它都带来了
Didn't know what you Iiked, so I just grabbed, you know, all of them.
好吧 你不喜欢花么 那算了 别管花了
OK. You don't Iike flowers? OK, forget the flowers.
你想干吗
What do you want?
我想也许我们可以 绕城市飞一圈
Thought maybe we could go for a Iittle flight around town.
让我们先互相了解一下
Get to know each other first.
你肯定会觉得很吓人吧
This must be very thrilling for you.
你以为你在干吗呀
What do you think you're doing?!
难道我飞太快啦 也许你是对的
Oh, am I moving too fast? You're probably right.
也许在开始浪漫之前 我应该先救你几次
I should just rescue you a few times before we get all romantic.
救到你了
Saved ya.
你很幸运能拥有这么伟大的英雄
You are Iucky to have such a great hero here.
- 你不许再… - 哦不 谁来帮帮忙啊
- Don't you ever... - Oh, no! Somebody do something!
哦 对啊 对啊 我救你 我救你
Oh, right, right, duh. I gotcha. I gotcha.
好悬啊 刚才 你差点就没命了
That was a close one. You almost died,
- 可我救了你 - 有建筑
- but I saved you. - Building!
接住你了 对不起啊 你刚说什么
Gotcha! I'm sorry. What were you saying?
我在救你的时候 就没注意听你说话了
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me saving your Iife.
放我下来 快
Put me down! Right now!
好吧 可以啦 好吧 等会儿
OK, all right. AII right, hold on.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我想我确实对你有点疯
I suppose I'm a, I'm a Iittle crazy, about you.
你到底是谁
Who are you, really?
哦 对 准备大开眼界吧 小姑娘
Oh, right. Well, prepare to have your mind blown, Iittle Iady.
- 哒哒 - 哈尔
- Ta-da. - Hal?
是啊 你不觉得很棒吗 现在什么也不能拆散我们了
Yeah. Isn't this great? Now there's nothing keeping us apart.
- 不 一点也不棒 - 喔 我们第一次吵架
- No. It's not great. - Wow. Our first fight.
我们的一切 就像婚后的老两口
This is so us. We're Iike an old married couple.
听着 这里没有“我们” 懂吗 永远都不会有“我们”
Look, there is no "us," OK? There will never be an "us."
可… 我有超能力啊
But... I have powers.
我有披风啊 我是好人呐
I have a cape. I'm the good guy.
你是个好人 哈尔 可你不懂
You are a good guy, Hal, but you don't understand.
- 我们得找出理由… - 不 不 这…
- We need to find out why... - No, no. This...
- 哈尔 深呼吸 - 这不公平
- Hal, just take a deep breath - This isn't right!
- 你先听我说 - 你应该是属于我的
- and Iisten to me for a moment. - You're supposed to be with me!
我正想警告你呢 哈尔
I'm trying to warn you, Hal.
是泰坦 我是泰坦 不是哈尔
It's Titan! It's Titan, not Hal!
- 伯纳德 - 罗珊
- Bernard. - Roxanne.
- 对不起我来晚了 - 喔 你的头发看起来很刺激
- Sorry I'm Iate. - Wow, your hair Iooks exciting.
还不是今晚最刺激的部分
Not the only exciting development of the night.
麦克迈制造了新超人 我知道为什么了
Megamind's created a new hero, and I know why.
一切都合理了 他很想念被虐的日子
It all makes sense now. He missed getting his butt kicked,
所以他创造了新超人…
so he created a new hero
- 来求虐 - 是嘛
- to kick it for him. - Yeah.
可他干吗选哈尔呢
But why would he pick Hal?
哈尔是他最不可能选的人啊
Hal is the worst possible person you could pick.
喔 要我接受那么多有点难啊
Wow. That's a Iot to take in.
我等快想懵了
It boggles my mind.
我更懵了 我肯定我们会…
I am extremely boggled. You know, I'm sure we'll get
搞清楚到底是谁虐谁吧
to the bottom of who's kicking whose butt.
可现在 我们还是 好好享受两人时光吧
But in the meantime, Iet's enjoy each other's company.
对不起 伯纳德 你说得对
I'm sorry, Bernard, of course, you're right.
是啊 我是该好好休息一下
You know, I could use a breather.
致伯纳德
To Bernard,
作为我颠倒夸张生活中的唯一正常事物
for being the only normal thing in my crazy, upside-down world.
为…正常干杯
To... being normal.
- 罗珊 - 什么事
- Roxanne? - Yes?
假如我并不那么正常
Say I wasn't so normal.
假如我是个秃头 而且肤色还有点…
Let's say I was bald and had the complexion of,
是很原始的肤色 但是路边随便某个人
of a popular primary color, as a random, nonspecific example.
- 你还会喜欢与我相伴吗 - 当然啦
- Would you still enjoy my company? - Of course!
不靠封面论书 不凭外貌看人
You don't judge a book by its cover or a person from the outside.
能听到这话真宽慰啊
That's a relief to hear.
而是根据这个人的行为举止 判定他的好坏
You judge them based on their actions.
听起来有点不够大气 不是吗
Well, that seems kind of petty, don't you think?
怎么 怎么啦
What? What?
别看我 是技术错误
Don't Iook at me! Just a technical glitch!
先别看 别介意哈
Don't Iook yet! Well, never mind that.
好了
OK.
我们说到哪儿了
Where were we?
- 你… - 你等会儿
- You... - Now, now, hold on.
你
You!
我可以解释的
I can explain!
那你说的那些话呢
What about everything you just said?
什么不靠书皮评书的好坏
About judging a book by its cover?
我们先看看书的内容 好不好
Well, Iet's take a Iook at the contents then, shall we?
你害死了城市超人 你抢走了这座城市…
You destroyed Metro Man, you took over the city,
然后 你竟然让我这么在意你
and then, you actually got me to care about you!
你为什么要这么邪恶 耍我吗
Why are you so evil? Tricking me?
你能得到什么好处
What could you possibly hope to gain?
等一会儿 我不敢相信
Wait a minute. I don't believe this.
你真以为我会和你在一起
Do you really think that I would ever be with you?
不
No.
好吧 宠物 你是对的
OK, Minion! You were right!
我是…不怎么对的
I was... Iess right!
应该坚持做好我们的专长 认真做个坏人
We should stick to what we're good at... being bad.
宠物
Minion?
你听着
You there!
对 是你
Yeah, you.
把黑色眼镜蛇带出来
Bring out the Black Mamba.
好的 泰坦 是时候言归正传了
OK, Titan. It's time to go down in style.
听说来了个新英雄 敢出来挑战我的邪恶
I hear there's a new hero who dares challenge my evil.
那个叫泰坦的人是谁啊
Where is the one they call Titan?
有种就来挑战我啊
Challenge me if you dare!
哦 不 我们要撞水啦
Oh no. We're gonna crash!
真是太尴尬了
This is embarrassing.
你也太欠考虑了 脑子有坑
Of all the inconsiderate, bone-headed...
太不负责任 太粗鲁…
...irresponsible, rude...
太不专业了吧
Unprofessional, that's what this is!
难道城市超人会让我等那么久吗
Would Metro Man have kept me waiting?
当然不会 他很专业的
Of course not! He was a pro!
嘿 麦克迈 我正想找你呢
Hey, Megamind! You're actually the guy I want to see.
还有啊 门在那里
Also, there's a door here.
你可知我等你等了多久
Do you have any idea how Iong I waited for you?
我很清楚你在说什么
No, no, no, I totally understand what you're saying.
你能不能先等一会儿 我正要把这级升了
Could you just, just shut up for one second. I'm trying to beat this Ievel.
你就没想过要怎么出场吗
Were you even planning on showing up?
这是什么
What's this?
这些东西你是哪儿弄来的
Where did you get all this stuff?
其实也不是我的
It doesn't belong to me.
- 你偷的 - 很酷是吧
- You stole it? - Pretty cool, right?
- 不 不 不 你可是英雄啊 - 废柴才当英雄呢
- No, no, no, no! You're a hero! - Being a hero is for Iosers!
就只会工作 工作 工作 不分日夜地工作 要干吗
It's work, work, work, 24/7, and for what?
我只是随便秀一把想把妞…
I only took the gig to get the girl,
可最后罗珊甚至都不想和我在一起
and it turns out Roxanne doesn't want anything to do with me.
- 罗珊.里奇 - 对啊 罗珊.里奇
- Roxanne Ritchi? - Yeah! Roxanne Ritchi!
我看见她摆这个痴痴的眼神…
I saw her having dinner and making googly eyes
跟某个书呆子吃饭呢
at some intellectual dweeb!
谁需要那么大动静
Who needs all that noise?
所以我觉得 我们应该联手
That's why I think we should team up.
你 等会儿 你要干吗
You... Wait... What?
有我的超能力 和你的聪明大脑
With my power, and your big-headedness,
- 我们就能统治全城啦 - 你想和我联手
- we could rule the city! - You want to team up?
我甚至都花了新的服装设计了
I even drew up some new costume designs, see?
- 服装设计 - 你是首脑
- Costume designs? - You'd be the brains,
所以你的脑袋很大
so you'd get a Iittle brain,
服装上就主攻眼镜
wearing glasses on your costume, or something.
因为我比较酷 所以我…
And since I'm the cool one, I'd have, Iike,
就戴两筒锐剑…
two tanks swordfighting...
我不敢相信
I can't believe you.
你的所有天赋 所有能力
AII your gifts, all your powers,
你竟然把它们浪费在私利上
and you... you squander them for your own personal gain.
- 没错 - 不 我才是罪犯
- Yes! - No! I'm the villain!
你才是好人 我做坏事…
You're the good guy! I do something bad,
你来抓我 所以我才创造了你
and you come and get me! That's why I created you.
是啊 没错 你个疯子 太空老爸告诉我…
Yeah, right. You're nuts. Space Dad told me...
听着 我就是你的太空老爸
Look, I'm your space dad!
你应该更像城市超人才是啊
You should be more Iike Metro Man.
- 你耍我 - 哦 不喜欢吗
- You tricked me? - Oh, don't Iike that?
还有呢
Well, there's more.
我还是和罗珊约会的书呆子呢
I'm also the intellectual dweeb dating Roxanne.
- 不 - 我们还激吻了呢
- No. - And we were smooching up a storm!
只要让我碰到你 我就…
When I get my hands on you, I'm gonna...
没错 我知道 让我接受正义审判
Yes! Yes, I know! Bring me to justice.
哦 老天 这一刻我等老久了
Oh God, how I've missed this.
英雄先出击啦
And the hero strikes the first blow.
但是罪恶起来反攻啦
But evil returns with a backhand!
没错
Yes!
来吧 你个小疯子
Come out, you Iittle freak!
我倒要看看你那大脑 被压倒在路面上是什么样子
I want to see what that big brain Iooks Iike on the pavement!
你就喜欢那些最老套的邪恶伎俩
You fell for the oldest evil trick in the book!
你个蓝色的小蠢蛋
You Iittle blue twerp!
当心啊
En garde!
哦 现在终于把握到宗旨啦
Oh, now that's the spirit!
我挡 我刺 我再挡
Parry! Thrust! Parry again!
听着 现在可以配上 妙趣横生的呛声
Now it's time for some witty back and forth banter!
你先呛
You go first!
哦 好吧 你都让我无话可说啦
OK! Look, I'm not sure where to go with that!
这招是为了你抢我女友
This one's for stealing my girlfriend!
这招是为了 你变“太空老爸”来戏弄我
This one's for Space Dad making a fool out of me!
最后 麦克迈 这招是为了太空继母 因为你也骗了她
And, Megamind, this one's for Space Stepmom! You Iied to her!
干得好 我觉得这场战斗 真是进展太顺利了
Well done. I thought that battle went really, really well.
- 我有几点建议 - 建议
- I mean, I have a few notes. - Notes?
可以等会儿再说 你先带我去监狱吧
But they can wait. You can take me to jail now.
哦不 我倒想带你去停尸房 你死定了
Oh, no, no, no. I was thinking more Iike the morgue. You're dead!
喔 喔… 这游戏你不能这么玩
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. This isn't how you play the game.
游戏结束
Game over.
(以防万一 按这里 ――宠物)
机器脑
Brain-bots!
我叫暂停
I'm calling time out!
暂停啊 暂停 暂停
Time out? Time out! Time out!
机器脑 启动故障安全装置
Brain-bots, initiate the fail-safe.
怎么样 傻大个 是用铜做的
Guess what, Buster Brown? It's made from copper.
你的力量抵御不了铜的
You're powerless against it.
是同一个金属打败… 城市超人的
It's the very same metal used to defeat... Metro Man?
不许再拿我跟城市超人做比较
You should stop comparing me to Metro Man!
躲得过初一 躲不过十五 麦克迈
You can run, Megamind, but you can't hide!
我们获救了 我们获救了
We're saved! We're saved!
你叫什么 新英雄
What's your name, new hero?
- 我叫泰坦 - 谢谢你
- It's Titan. - Thank you!
谢谢你 泰坦让我们自由啦
Thank you! Titan has freed us!
哦 换做我就不会说“自由” 这更像是接受新掌权
Oh, I wouldn't say "free." More Iike under new management.
- 你想干吗 - 泰坦变坏了
- What do you want? - Titan's turned evil.
祝贺你 又一个天才计划回火了吧
Congratulations. Another one of your genius plans has backfired on you.
我的门卫怎么会让你上来啊
And why did my doorman Iet you up?
卡洛斯
Carlos.
求你了 罗珊 不要 不要 我需要你的帮助
Please, Roxanne, no. No. I need your help.
你为什么需要我的帮助
Why do you need my help?
因为你是我认识的人中 最聪明的了
Because you're the smartest person I know.
可你不能躲在这里
But you can't hide here.
铜应该有效啊 怎么会失效了呢
The copper should have worked. Why didn't the copper work?
上次就是铜起效的啊
The copper worked perfectly well Iast time.
铜 你说话没道理啊
Copper? You're not making any sense.
如果我们不找到泰坦的弱点
Look, if we don't find Titan's weakness,
他会把全城都给毁了
he'll destroy the whole city.
- 好吧 我要怎么帮你 - 我们需要找到答案
- OK, how can I help? - We need to find answers.
你最了解城市超人了 他有藏身之处吗 比如洞穴
You knew Metro Man best. Did he have a hideout? A cave?
偏僻的堡垒什么的 只要能提供线索就行
A solitary fortress of some kind? Anything that would give us clues.
呃 我倒是知道一个地方
Well... there is one place I know.
你给他超能力 就不能收回吗
You gave him these powers. Can't you just take them away?
不行 消散枪我放隐形车里 可我把车弄丢了
I can't. I Iost my diffuser gun when I misplaced the invisible car.
就在那晚 你甩了我 留我一人 在雨里
The night you dumped me. Alone. In the rain.
你就没回想过吗
Did you ever Iook back?
- 没有 - 哦 我硕大的蓝脑子
- No! - My giant blue head!
我看我们到了
I guess we're here.
所以 他竟然藏在了这里
So, this is where he hid it.
都那么多年了 我过去的“交舍”
After all these years. My old shoolhouse.
(小天才学校)
我觉得你得为那一晚做的事情道歉
You know, I think there's an apology in order for the other night.
那敢情好 不过我们现在得快点
OK, that would be nice, but make it quick.
我们手头上还有很多 紧急事件要处理
We have much more pressing matters to deal with.
不敢相信他都还收着
Wow. I can't believe he kept all this stuff.
啊 我记得他是穿过那个
I remember when he wore that.
- 别看那些有的没的 - 哦 对啊 专心点
- Shouldn't we try to stay focused here? - Yes, of course. Right. Focused.
嘿 快过来看这个
Hey. Come over and Iook at this.
什么东西 发现什么啦
What is it? What did you find?
你看
Look.
这杯子里有冰块耶
This glass has ice cubes in it.
是啊 因为水遇冷会结冰
Yes, that's what happens when water gets cold.
我想说的是 你不觉得 冰块到现在都没化…
No, what I'm saying is, don't you think it's a Iittle odd
有点奇怪
that the ice hasn't melted yet?
人生又一大奇迹
One of Iife's great mysteries.
嘿
Hey.
现在我们有确凿的证据
We now have confirmed reports.
一开始本以为泰坦是大英雄 现在已成了恶魔
Titan, first thought to be this city's new hero, has turned evil.
城市从没遭遇如此大的毁坏
The city has never seen this level of destruction.
真希望城市超人能还活着
If only Metro Man were still alive.
- 你还活着？ - 你竟然活着
- You're alive? - You're alive.
- 我还活着啊 - 可我 我们…
- I'm alive. - But I, we...
我们都看到你的骷髅啦 你已经死啦
We saw your skeleton! You were dead!
你是鬼魂么
Are you a ghost?
这其中最好有什么 超级合理的解释
There had better be an amazing explanation for this.
说话 幽灵
Speak, apparition.
好吧 好吧 好吧
OK. OK, OK, OK.
你们是应该知道真相
You both deserve the truth.
一切都得从天文台那次说起
It all started back at the observatory.
罗珊被绑架了 我想阻止你
Roxanne was kidnapped. I was gonna stop you.
可我那天真没心情跟你玩游戏
My head wasn't in the game that day.
感觉像是在应付某种套路
We were kind of going through the motions.
于是 我决定用超高速…
So... using my super-speed,
好理清我的思路
I decided to go clear my head.
开火
Fire!
于是我发现…
Then I realized,
我们这一生都在重复 这些愚蠢的游戏
we had done this same silly charade our entire lives.
我想把这种奇怪的心情 驱逐出去
I tried to get my mind off how I was feeling,
可我心里就是堵得慌
but I just felt stuck.
我开始发现 尽管自己有那么多超能力
I began to realize, despite all my powers,
可每一个市民都有一样 我没有的东西 就是一个选择
each and every citizen of Metro had something I didn't: a choice.
自我记事起 从来都是 城市要我干吗我就干吗
Ever since I can remember, I've always had to be what the city wanted me to be.
那谁来成全我的愿望
But what about what I wanted to do?
突然我就想通了
Then it suddenly hit me.
我还是有选择的
I do have a choice.
我想做什么 我就能做什么
I can be whatever I want to be.
没人说英雄这件事 必须得是毕生的演出
No one said this hero thing had to be a lifetime gig.
可你也不能宣布退出
You can't just quit, either.
于是我想到了一个绝妙的主意: 假装我死了
That's when I got the brilliant idea... to fake my death.
铜会吸收我的能量
Copper drains my powers.
你的弱点是铜？
Your weakness is copper?
你的死亡射线发射的时候 我从没感到那么有活力过
Once your death ray hit, I'd never felt so alive.
于是我从附近的护士学校 借来了一具骷髅
So I borrowed a prop from a nearby nursing school.
城市超人终于死了
Metro Man was finally dead.
然后音乐大师诞生
And Music Man was born!
- 音乐大师？ - 我的独家标记
- Music Man? - That way I could keep my Iogo.
- 因为什么 - 再说一遍
- 'Cause of wha...? - Come again?
我终于能触及 我最真实的能力了:
I was finally free to get in touch with my true power...
玩弄歌词的天赋
...weaving Iyrical magic.
你听着这个
Check this out.
我有双慧眼
I have eyes that can see
可以透过铅看见你
Right through lead...
- 你太可怕了 - 当然 你是有天赋
- You're horrible! - Granted, you have talent.
可现在有个疯子在外面 摧残我们的… 你的城市
But there's a madman out there destroying our... your city.
你怎么能这样
How could you do this?!
这个城市的市民是如此信任你 你却抛弃了他们
The people of this city relied on you, and you deserted them!
你竟然把我们拱手让给这个人
You Ieft us in the hands of him!
- 恕我冒昧 - 没关系 我支持你
- No offense. - No, I'm with you.
我们需要你的帮助
Look, we need your help.
很抱歉 我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I really am.
我不干了
I'm done.
你也知道 小兄弟 阳有它对应的阴
You know, Iittle buddy, there's a yin for every yang.
如果有坏人 总会有好人出来反抗
If there's bad, good will rise up against it.
我找了好久才找到 自己人生的归属
It's taken me a Iong time to find my calling.
现在也该换你去寻找你的归属
Now it's about time you find yours.
真是的 谁需要他啊
Hey, who needs him?
我们靠自己也能打败泰坦
We can beat Titan ourselves.
我说我们干脆回到邪恶巢穴 找些激光枪…
I say we go back to the evil Iair, grab some ray guns,
然后两面夹击 靠你那些武器搞定他
hold him sideways, and just go all gangsta on him.
不行的
We can't.
所以你就这样不干了
So that's it? You're just giving up?
我是坏人 我不会在白天救人 日落时自豪地飞入天际
I'm the bad guy. I don't save the day, I don't fly off into the sunset,
我还不该有女朋友
and I don't get the girl.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
要是再没人来帮助我们 全城都将沦陷
Unless someone comes to our aid soon, all may be lost.
千万市民已在大浪潮中逃离本市
Thousands have already fled the city in a mass exodus.
留下来的市民们 我们也警告他们 要呆在室内等待新的指示
Remaining citizens are warned to stay indoors until further notice.
政府已发出警告…
Authorities have issued a warning
要求各位不惜一切 远离市中心
to stay out of the downtown area at all costs.
(泰坦城)
哈尔
Hal!
让我猜猜 因为看见我这么强悍…
Let me guess. After seeing how awesome I am,
你终于弄懂自己想要什么了吧 我告诉你 我早就不想你了
you've finally come to your senses? Well, I'm over you.
- 我是来阻止你的 哈尔 - 你 就凭你
- I've come to stop you, Hal. - You? Oh, wow.
你想把我怎样 把我报道到死
OK, what are you gonna do, report me to death?
我是想跟你讲道理
I was going to try reasoning with you.
我们一起工作了那么久 我很了解你
You and I, we worked together for a Iong time. I know you.
你才不了解我 你从没花时间了解过我
You don't know me. You never took the time to know me.
今天算是我们第一次正式外出…
This is the first time we've hung out socially,
而我现在正准备把全城给毁了
and it's when I'm about to destroy the city!
我现在是想和真正的哈尔说话
I want to talk to the real Hal.
那位真心喜欢摄影的家伙…
I want to talk to the guy who Ioved being a cameraman,
那个爱吃沙司 有点宅的哈尔
and eating dip, and being a nerd,
而不是现在这个吓人的泰坦哈尔
and being not as scary as the Tighten Hal.
太晚啦
Too Iate!
中断我们的行程…
...interrupting our scheduled...
奇怪事件正在发生…
...extraordinary events taking place...
全村的高温…
Heat in the valley and...
麦克迈
Megamind!
你和我还有未尽的问题要解决
You and I have some unfinished business.
我在都市高塔等你
I'll be waiting at Metro Tower.
希望你不会看到后软腿
Oh, and just so you don't get cold feet...
罗珊
Roxanne.
来吧 珊珊 呼唤你的英雄来拯救你
Come on, Roxie, call for your hero to come rescue you.
麦克迈 不知道你有没有在听 可如果你听到了…
Megamind, I don't even know if you're listening, but if you are,
你决不能这么放弃
you can't give up.
我所认识的麦克迈 绝不会逃避任何一场战斗
The Megamind I knew would never have run from a fight,
即使他知道自己没有一丝胜算
even when he knew he had absolutely no chance of winning.
这才是你最根本的品质
It was your best quality.
你赶紧变成那个人回来吧
You need to be that guy right now.
这个城市需要你
The city needs you.
我需要你
I need you.
罗珊
Roxanne.
我给你一个小时
You have one hour.
别让我等久了
Don't keep me waiting.
沃登 沃登 听我说 你这次必须得放我走
Warden! Warden! Listen to me! You have to Iet me go!
我必须阻止泰坦
Tighten has to be stopped!
对不起 麦克迈 你有88条无期徒刑
Sorry, Megamind. You still have 88 Iife sentences to go.
这么长的时间 都归结于你的所作所为
Plenty of time to reflect on what you've done.
你不是想听我说那句话吗 我会说的
Did you want to hear me say it? I'll say it.
你听着 我内心最黑暗处在呼唤:
Here it is, from the blackest part of my heart.
我很抱歉
I am sorry!
不买账
Not buying it.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我不知道威胁过 这座城市多少次了
I've terrorized this city countless times.
创造了一个英雄 最后竟变成一个罪犯
Created a hero who's turned out to be a villain.
我对罗珊撒谎 还有…
I Iied to Roxanne, and...
我的挚友宠物 我像脏土一样对他
...my best friend Minion, I treated Iike dirt.
请别让这座城市…
Please don't make this city...
别让罗珊因为我的过错 而付出代价
...don't make Roxanne pay for my wrongdoings.
接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
哦 宠物 你这只帅气的鱼
Oh, Minion, you fantastic fish, you.
我们还等什么 赶紧走咯
What are we waiting for? We'd better get going.
你整到我了
You got me.
- 祝你们好运 - 我们死定啦
- Good Iuck, fellas! - We're gonna die!
等会儿 什么
Wait, what?
嘿 都市废柴 这里是都市高塔
Hey, Metro losers. This is Metro Tower.
听说这里应该是 本市力量的象征
They say it's supposed to be a symbol of our city's strength.
可对我来说 这总能使我想起…
But for me, it's a reminder of the day
这女人曾经残暴地撕碎我的心 令人厌恶的回忆
this woman ferociously ripped out my heart. And I hate reminders!
救命啊
Help!
别这样好不好 我知道你内心还是存善的
Please don't do this. I know there's still good in you, Hal.
你太天真了 珊珊
You're so naive, Roxie.
你看见谁都会觉得他好 即使他是个彻头彻尾的坏蛋
You see the good in everybody, even when it's not there.
你只活在幻想之中
You're Iiving a fantasy.
这世上没有复活兔 没有牙仙…
There is no Easter Bunny, there is no Tooth Fairy,
也没有英国女皇
and there is no Queen of England.
这可是现实世界 拜托你清醒点吧
This is the real world, and you need to wake up!
你敢挑战麦克迈吗
You dare challenge Megamind?
一山不容二虎
This town isn't big enough for two super-villains!
你确实算是虎 可惜不够威猛
Oh, you're a villain all right! Just not a super one!
是吗 有何差别
Yeah? What's the difference?
秀给他看
Presentation!
- 我就知道你会回来 - 我们是搭档啊
- I knew you'd come back. - Well, that made one of us.
- 你有何计划 - 反正不要死就是了
- What's the plan? - Well, it mostly involves not dying.
那我喜欢
I Iike that plan.
小心建筑
Building!
快点 你速度再快点
Go faster! Make this thing go faster!
我控制不了了
I can't control it!
不
No.
现在轻松多了
Well, that was easy.
看来只剩一样还未了结
Looks Iike there's only one Ioose end now.
拜托你给予我们的公共交通工具 一点尊重好不好
Please, Iet's have a Iittle respect for public transportation.
你回来了
You came back!
你说得对 罗珊 我不该离开
You were right, Roxanne. I never should have Ieft.
我…我以为你死了
I... I thought you were dead.
我的死看来是过分夸大了
My death was... greatly exaggerated.
那么 你就是我听说的那个废柴吧
So, you're the punk I've heard about.
对不起 我已经尽力了
I'm sorry. I did the best I could.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
宠物
Minion?
惊喜吧
Surprise!
他才是真正的英雄
He's the real hero.
麦克迈
Megamind.
你还想去哪儿
Going somewhere?
…除了监狱以外
Besides jail?
不要 你别打脸 伙计 求你
No, not in the face, man. Please.
知道你现在还有什么出路吗 那就是远离大兜市
If you know what's good for you, Tighten, you'll stay out of Metrocity!
- 没问题 - 永远
- You got it! - For good!
真卑鄙啊 大姐
Pretty sneaky, sis.
可我记得只有一个人 会把本市称作“大兜市”
But there's only one person I know who calls this town "Metrocity."
就是你
You.
你觉得很好笑是吗
Bet you think it's really funny?
你们就都这么嘲笑真正强悍的人
Let's all Iaugh at the really cool guy?
反正你能笑的时间也不久了
Well, you're not gonna be Iaughing for Iong.
隐形车
The invisible car.
嘿 你记不记得我甩你的那天晚上
Hey! Remember that night that I dumped you?
你现在跟我提这个
You're bringing this up now?
其实我是回想过了啦
Well, I did Iook back!
真的吗 真的吗
You did? You did?
是啊 所以现在该轮到你 回想看看了
Yes! And you should Iook back right now!
哦 我懂了
Oh, I get it!
这绝对是你最后一次嘲弄我了
This is the Iast time you make a fool out of me!
我让你成为英雄的
I made you a hero.
一切嘲弄都是你一手造成的
You did the fool thing all by yourself.
你真可悲啊
You're so pathetic.
不管你是什么样的人 你都永远那么失败
No matter what side you're on, you're always the Ioser.
失败还是有好处的
There's a benefit to Iosing.
失败能让你吸取教训
You get to Iearn from your mistakes.
啊 不会到现在还耍我吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
宠物 如果我还能活着 我肯定杀了你
Minion, if I Iive, I will kill you.
祝你飞行愉快
Enjoy your flight!
麦克迈
Megamind!
于是 一切都这么结束了
So this is how it ends.
换做平常 我肯定会将此 归结为我最后一次光辉的战败
Normally, I'd chalk this up to my last glorious failure.
但今天不是
But not today.
怎么说呢 本性难移吧
What can I say? Old habits die hard.
(脱水)
说再见咯 珊珊
Say bye-bye, Roxie.
李好
OIIo.
(消散)
坏人到最后是不会有好下场的
The thing about bad guys, they always Iose!
- 你办到了 你赢了 - 呃…
- You did it. You won. - Well...
终于有胜利的理由了――你
I finally had a reason to win. You.
宠物
Minion!
看不见了 好冷 又好热 好黑 又好亮
Can't see. It's cold and... warm, and dark and Iight.
是我 宠物 我在这儿
It's me, Minion. I'm right here.
我们共同经历了许多冒险 你还有我
We've had a Iot of adventures together, you and I.
确实 宠物
We have, Minion.
虽说… 大多数都以惨败告终
I mean... most of them ended in horrible failure,
可今天我们赢了 不是吗 少爷
but we won today. Didn't we, sir?
是啊 我们赢了 多亏了你
Yes, Minion, we did it. Thanks to you.
暗号: 我们现在是好人了
Code: We're The Good Guys Now.
暗号: 我看是的
Code: I Guess We Are.
哦 哦 哦 我要走了 我看是时候到了
Oh, oh, oh, I'm going! I think this, this is it!
我走了 我走远了…
I'm going... going far...
真会制造戏剧效果
What a drama queen.
知道吗 我现在感觉好多了 看来刚才是该到水里游会儿
You know, I'm feeling much better now. I guess I just needed a swim.
他整到你了 对吧
He had you, didn't he?
经典的宠物 别摆那张脸
Classic Minion. Don't give me that face.
他总是靠他那小脸惹女生欢心
He reels you in with that Iittle face.
- 看看那张脸 - 我们成功了
- Look at that face. - We did it!
我们成功了
We did it!
- 胜利 - 你成功了
- Fist pump! - You did it!
赢了 赢了 赢了
We won, we won, we won!
后退 你们这群野蛮人
Get back, you savages!
对不起 对不起 他只是不大习惯 正常地回应大家
Sorry! Sorry. He's just not used to positive feedback.
有趣的是 我认为天命 一条已为我们铺成的道路
Funny, I guess destiny is not the path given to us...
而要看我们自己的选择
...but the path we choose for ourselves.
好吧 把手举高
AII right, put your hands in the air.
现在把钱包都拿出来
Now hand over your wallets.
开玩笑的啦
I'm just kidding!
开玩笑啦
Just kidding!
我得承认 做好人确实更诱人
I have to admit, being good has its perks.
知道吗 你穿白色衣服很好看
You know, you Iook pretty good in white.
麦克迈 您能否…
Megamind, if you plea...
嘿 我的孩子看不到啦
Hey. My kid can't see.
对不起啊 我的朋友
Sorry, my friend.
没错 小伙计 就知道你有这天赋
Way to go, Iittle buddy. I knew he had it in him.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
麦克迈 大都市的保卫者
Megamind, defender of Metro City!
这么说我 我还真喜欢
You know, I like the sound of that.
音乐
Hit it!
因为我很坏 我很坏 来吧
Because I'm bad, I'm bad Come on
非常非常坏
Really, really bad
我很坏 我很坏 你知道的
You know I'm bad, I'm bad You know it
麦克迈 麦克迈…
Megamind! Megamind! Megamind! Megamind!
全世界现在都得回答
And the whole world has to answer right now
现在再说一遍
Just to tell you once again
你知道 我很坏 我很坏
You know I'm bad, I'm bad
我很坏 我很坏 没错
I'm bad! I'm bad! That's right. Yeah!
你知道的 你知道的
You know it, you know it
你知道 你知道
You know, you know
全世界现在都得回答
And the whole world has to answer right now
再告诉我一遍 谁最坏
Just to tell you once again Who's bad
(麦克迈 大都市的保卫者)
【后面还有内容】
The word is out You're doing wrong
Gonna lock you up Before too long
Your lying eyes Gonna tell you right
So listen up Don't make a fight
Your talk is cheap You're not a man
You're throwing stones To hide your hands
But they say The sky's the limit
And to me that's really true
And my friends You have seen nothing
Just wait till I get through
Because I'm bad, I'm bad Come on
Really, really bad
You know I'm bad, I'm bad You know it
You know I'm bad, I'm bad You know it, you know
And the whole world has to answer right now
Just to tell you once again
You know I'm bad, I'm bad Come on
Really, really bad
You know I'm bad, I'm bad You know it, you know it
You know, you know You know, come on
And the whole world has to answer right now
Just to tell you once again
You know I'm smooth, I'm bad You know it
Really, really bad
You know I'm bad I'm bad
You know, you know You know it, come on
And the whole world has to answer right now
Just to tell you once again Who's bad
【后面还有内容】
翻译: justseven 校订:
交流邮箱: jmtrans94@tom.com
少爷 你真该养成 检查口袋的好习惯
Sir, you really need to empty your pockets more often.
今天真是过得太恐怖了
This has been the worst day of my entire Iife.
不用担心啦
No worries.